Up until this point,
到现在为止
we looked at a number of clustering methods.
我们已经了解了一些聚类方法
But choosing a clustering method is only one step in
但如果我们希望将所掌握的数据集
a multi-step process that hopefully
转化为知识和信息
turns the dataset that we have into knowledge and information.
选择聚类方法只是众多步骤中的一步
So let's look at this cluster analysis process.
那么我们来看看这个聚类分析过程
The first step is usually feature selection and feature extraction.
第一步通常是特征选择和特征提取
Feature selection is choosing distinguishing features from a set of candidates.
特征选择是从一组候选特征中选择特征
We don't have to throw all of our dataset,
我们不必对所有的数据集 即数据集的每一列
every column of our dataset at the clustering method.
都使用聚类方法
Sometimes we have thousands of dimensions for a dataset.
有时我们的数据集有数以千计的维度
And so running a clustering would take a lot of resources.
进行聚类需要很多资源
So there are ways and tools we can use to reduce the number of
我们可以使用一些方法和工具来减少特征
features and select the best ones that would result in,
并选取结果最好的特征
hopefully, the best clustering.
希望得到最好的聚类
That is feature selection.
这就是特征选取
Feature extraction is transforming the data to generate novel and useful features.
特征提取是对数据进行转换 以生成新的有用特征
The best example of this is PCA or principle component analysis,
最好的例子是 PCA 即主成分分析
which we will look at in a future lesson in this nanodegree program.
这点我们将在将来的课程中进行学习
The second step is to choose a clustering algorithm. We've seen a few of them.
第二步是选择一个聚类算法 聚类算法我们已经看过一些
And based on what you need to do and how your data looks,
根据你需要做什么和数据的外观
you'll have to experiment with whichever ones can give you the better result.
你必须试验哪一个算法可以给你更好的结果
No algorithm is universally applicable to every problem we may face.
没有任何算法可以普遍地适用于我们可能面临的问题
It is also in this step that we have to choose a proximity measure.
在这一步 我们必须选择一个邻近度度量
So throughout this lesson,
所以在这节课中
we have been using Euclidean distance as a measure of
我们将一直使用欧式距离
how close two points are in a sort of geometric sense.
来衡量两点间的几何距离
But if, say, your data is actually documents or word embeddings,
但如果你的数据是文档或词嵌入
your proximity measure will have to be cosine distance.
邻近度度量将是余弦距离
If your data is more of a gene expression type data,
如果你的数据更多的是基因表达类型数据
you'd be using Pearson's correlation.
那么你将使用 Pearson 相关系数
The proximity measure is usually something we
我们通常会说 邻近度度量是
pass to the clustering algorithm where we'd say,
我们传递给聚类算法的东西
"All right, here's the data.
好的 这是数据
Here's the number of clusters," let's say and use
这是聚类的数量
this proximity measure to calculate the distance between the points.
我们就用邻近度度量来计算点之间的距离吧
The third step is cluster validation,
第三步是聚类评价
and that is evaluating how well a clustering turn out to be.
就是评估一个聚类的效果如何
So in addition to visualizing a clustering result when possible,
因此 除了在可能的情况下对聚类结果进行可视化以外
we can also use a number of scoring methods to evaluate
我们还可以使用一些评分方法来评估
the quality of the clustering structure based on certain criteria.
基于特定标准的聚类结构的质量
These scoring methods are called indices.
这些评分方法被称为指数
So each of them is called a clustering validation index,
每一个指数称为聚类有效性指标
and this will be the topic of the next few videos.
这将是下几节视频中将要学习的主题
Before we talk about validations,
在谈论聚类评价之前
look at the last step which is results interpretation.
我们来看最后一步 聚类结果解释
And this is determining what insights we can
结果解释就决定了我们
glean from the resulting clustering structure.
可以从最终的聚类结构中学习到什么样的见解
This is a step that needs domain expertise to give
这一步骤需要领域专业知识为集群提供标签
labels to the clusters and try to infer some insight out of them.
并试图从中推断出一些见解
So let's take a step back and look at cluster validation.
接着让我们回到上一步继续学习聚类评价